<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on icyphox</title>
    <link>https://icyphox.github.io/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on icyphox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 21:15:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://icyphox.github.io/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into the core: Atmospheric metalcore</title>
      <link>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/atmosphericore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 21:15:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/atmosphericore/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched the metalcore topic in quite a while, so I decided I&amp;rsquo;d write about one of my most faviourite sub-subgenres &amp;ndash; atmospheric metalcore.
What makes an atmospheric metalcore band? Considering that metalcore is a pretty niche subgenre of metal, atmospheric metalcore is the nichest of the niche. So there isn&amp;rsquo;t any specifics as to what defines atmospheric metalcore. But most atmospheric metalcore bands share a few common features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthwave</title>
      <link>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/synthwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 22:00:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/synthwave/</guid>
      <description>Synthwave, also called New Retro Wave or just Retrowave, is an epic genre I just got into. It mainly appeals to me because of it&amp;rsquo;s cyberpunk-ish feel. The whole theme of this genre is that retro futuristic feel, y&amp;rsquo;know, that whole idea of a very dark city, with huge tall towers, with flying-cars&amp;hellip; Essentially a Tron-like thing.
There are 2 primary styles in synthwave, one&amp;rsquo;s a very dark perspective, kinda like Terminator, and one&amp;rsquo;s a very positive/relaxing style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why People Hate Metalcore</title>
      <link>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/hatemetalcore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 19:18:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/hatemetalcore/</guid>
      <description>This is going to be an interesting topic to talk about. Why did I pick this? Primarily because I love this genre of music, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve the hate it gets, even from some of the so called elitist metalhead communities. So how did this all start? It all began in the early 2000s, with the scene kids.
Scene Kids In the early 2000s there existed a special kind of rebellious teenagers, termed as &amp;ldquo;scene kids&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Into Metalcore</title>
      <link>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/gettingintometalcore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 17:05:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://icyphox.github.io/blog/gettingintometalcore/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned metalcore a couple of times, what is it? Metalcore is a genre of extreme music, which blends hardcore punk and metal. This turns to sound much heavier than normal metal. Metalcore has a few interesting characteristics that sets it apart from mainstream metal.
First off, breakdowns. This is a huge difference between the two, mainly because it adds a bit more heaviness to the music. Breakdowns can, in some ways be compared to bass drops.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>